<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on motmaytinh</title>
    <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on motmaytinh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 10:08:00 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://motmaytinh.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Musing</title>
      <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/musing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://motmaytinh.github.io/musing/</guid>
      <description>🍵 Jun 4, 2021
&amp;ldquo;The Answer to the Great Question&amp;hellip; Of Life, the Universe and Everything&amp;hellip; Is&amp;hellip; Forty-two.&amp;rdquo; said Deep Thought, with infinite majesty and calm.
— Douglas Adams, The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy
   🍵 May 27, 2020
&amp;ldquo;Because it&amp;rsquo;s the thought of Mecca that keeps me alive. That&amp;rsquo;s what helps me face these days that are all the same, these mute crystals on the shelves, and lunch and dinner at that same horrible cafe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://motmaytinh.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m currently a Software Engineer at Zalo working as a backend engineer. I studied Computer Science at the Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology.
I have a thrist for knowledge and learning new things.
Feel free to drop me a message if you want to know more about me. 😜
 Personal I love making new friends with people around the world 📬; photography 📷; reading books 📚; listening to instrumental music 🎹; running 🏃; inline skating 🛼</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rendezvous Hashing, một thuật toán khác thay thế Consistent Hashing</title>
      <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2021/03/rendezvous-hashing-m%E1%BB%99t-thu%E1%BA%ADt-to%C3%A1n-kh%C3%A1c-thay-th%E1%BA%BF-consistent-hashing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 10:08:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2021/03/rendezvous-hashing-m%E1%BB%99t-thu%E1%BA%ADt-to%C3%A1n-kh%C3%A1c-thay-th%E1%BA%BF-consistent-hashing/</guid>
      <description>Khoan, Consistent Hashing là gì? À, bài viết này nhằm mục đích giới thiệu Rendezvous Hashing (Highest Random Weight Hashing), một thuật toán có thể thay thế cho thuật toán “trứ danh” Consistent Hashing. Nếu bạn chưa từng nghe về Consistent Hashing và bài toán mà nó giải quyết thì có thể tham khảo qua bài viết dễ đọc và dễ hiểu này trước khi đi vào nội dung chính.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS 101</title>
      <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2020/08/rss-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 10:08:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2020/08/rss-101/</guid>
      <description>If you like to collect wisdom from blogs like me, you probably have experienced when: having too many blogs to follow and not knowing when a new post comes out. The primitive manual way to do is regularly loop through the bookmarked blogs to find if there are any updates. Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s not the way we developer comply with, most of you will think of writing a crawler, automating the process and notify when new content had been published.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I wrote a python wrapper for Java implementation of VnCoreNLP</title>
      <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2019/06/how-i-wrote-a-python-wrapper-for-java-implementation-of-vncorenlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 07:01:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2019/06/how-i-wrote-a-python-wrapper-for-java-implementation-of-vncorenlp/</guid>
      <description>When working on my thesis, I have to experiment with different tokenize tool. One of those is VnCoreNLP which is reported to have very high accuracy. The thing is it&amp;rsquo;s written in Java while my pipeline is written in Python. So, I decided to write a python wrapper for it. Let&amp;rsquo;s go.
FYI: If you don&amp;rsquo;t know it yet, the problem of calling other programming language is interoperability. For example, Java can call native functions written in C/C++ using JNI.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
