<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on motmaytinh</title>
    <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on motmaytinh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 07:01:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://motmaytinh.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Musing</title>
      <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/musing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://motmaytinh.github.io/musing/</guid>
      <description>🍵 May 27, 2020
&amp;ldquo;Because it&amp;rsquo;s the thought of Mecca that keeps me alive. That&amp;rsquo;s what helps me face these days that are all the same, these mute crystals on the shelves, and lunch and dinner at that same horrible cafe. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that if my dream is realized, I&amp;rsquo;ll have no reason to go on living.&amp;rdquo;
— Paulo Coelho, The Alchemist
   🍵 May 4, 2020</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://motmaytinh.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m currently a Software Engineer at Zalo working as a backend engineer. I studied Computer Science at the Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology. I was always interested in how things work under the hood.
Feel free to drop me a message if you want to know more about me. 😜
 Personal I love making new friends with people around the world; photography 📷; reading books 📚; listening to instrumental music 🎹.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I wrote a python wrapper for Java implementation of VnCoreNLP</title>
      <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2019/06/how-i-wrote-a-python-wrapper-for-java-implementation-of-vncorenlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 07:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2019/06/how-i-wrote-a-python-wrapper-for-java-implementation-of-vncorenlp/</guid>
      <description>When working on my thesis, I have to experiment on different tokenize tool. One of those is VnCoreNLP which is reported to have very high accuracy. The thing is it&amp;rsquo;s written in Java while my pipeline is written in Python. So, I decided to write a python wrapper for it. Let&amp;rsquo;s go.
FYI: If you don&amp;rsquo;t know it yet, the problem of calling others programming language is interoperability. For example, Java can call native function written in C/C++ using JNI.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>