<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on motmaytinh</title>
    <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on motmaytinh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 10:16:00 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://motmaytinh.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Awesome blog posts</title>
      <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2022/05/awesome-blog-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 10:16:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2022/05/awesome-blog-posts/</guid>
      <description>These are blog posts I read over the years. Some of them explain concepts in a way that’s easy to understand. Some discuss common pitfalls/misunderstandings which are helpful for a newbie. There are also some blogs that I like to read. They either have witty or neat content.
Networking  How NAT traversal works How CDN works  Programming  Explaining dynamic programming to a 4 year old  Kafka  A gentle introduction to Apache Kafka  Docker  10 Myths About Docker That Stop Developers Cold  Git  How to Write a Git Commit Message CHERRY-PICKING SPECIFIC COMMITS FROM ANOTHER BRANCH  Blogs  wizard zines : Explaining programming concepts in a comical way Lam Do : Tips and guides for preparing and conducting interview Alex Xu : Explain complex systems with simple terms  (To be updated&amp;hellip;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rendezvous Hashing, một thuật toán khác thay thế Consistent Hashing</title>
      <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2021/03/rendezvous-hashing-m%E1%BB%99t-thu%E1%BA%ADt-to%C3%A1n-kh%C3%A1c-thay-th%E1%BA%BF-consistent-hashing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 10:08:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2021/03/rendezvous-hashing-m%E1%BB%99t-thu%E1%BA%ADt-to%C3%A1n-kh%C3%A1c-thay-th%E1%BA%BF-consistent-hashing/</guid>
      <description>Khoan, Consistent Hashing là gì? À, bài viết này nhằm mục đích giới thiệu Rendezvous Hashing (Highest Random Weight Hashing), một thuật toán có thể thay thế cho thuật toán “trứ danh” Consistent Hashing. Nếu bạn chưa từng nghe về Consistent Hashing và bài toán mà nó giải quyết thì có thể tham khảo qua bài viết dễ đọc và dễ hiểu này trước khi đi vào nội dung chính.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS 101</title>
      <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2020/08/rss-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 10:08:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2020/08/rss-101/</guid>
      <description>If you like to collect wisdom from blogs like me, you probably have experienced when: having too many blogs to follow and not knowing when a new post comes out. The primitive manual way to do is regularly loop through the bookmarked blogs to find if there are any updates. Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s not the way we developer comply with, most of you will think of writing a crawler, automating the process and notify when new content had been published.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I wrote a python wrapper for Java implementation of VnCoreNLP</title>
      <link>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2019/06/how-i-wrote-a-python-wrapper-for-java-implementation-of-vncorenlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 07:01:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://motmaytinh.github.io/2019/06/how-i-wrote-a-python-wrapper-for-java-implementation-of-vncorenlp/</guid>
      <description>When working on my thesis, I have to experiment with different tokenize tool. One of those is VnCoreNLP which is reported to have very high accuracy. The thing is it&amp;rsquo;s written in Java while my pipeline is written in Python. So, I decided to write a python wrapper for it. Let&amp;rsquo;s go.
FYI: If you don&amp;rsquo;t know it yet, the problem of calling other programming language is interoperability. For example, Java can call native functions written in C/C++ using JNI.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
